So for these handles that I'm using on this chicken baker I have done them with an extruder.
That's why they look so even and they have a nice textural design to them.
An extruder is a lot like a giant Play Dough factory, it just squeezes out one very long consistent piece of clay, and I like to use that a lot for many of my different handles.
So the first thing I need to do is prepare the clay for the extruder.
Now my extruder has a 4 inch cylindrical barrel, so I need to get a piece of clay that's going to fit in there nicely.
So I'm going to cut a piece off.
And then I'm going to pound it on the table, to round out the corners.
And then I'm going to pat to elongate it and thin it out just a little bit more.
Now I want it to be smaller than the actual size of the barrel of the extruder itself so that it will slip in there really easily and it won't get jammed or anything like that.
So now the clay is prepared and I'll show you over at the extruder how this works.